Hook. You can get free Overture Maps building data in 30 seconds. No Python, no terminal.
Platform. YouTube 16.9. Duration. 75s.
Audience. GIS Analyst. Section 1. Hook. 0.0.5.
You already know Overture Maps data is free. The problem is actually getting it out.
Section 2. Problem 0.05 to 0.20.
The official workflow? Install Python, set up a virtual ENV, figure out your bounding box coordinates, run a CLI command, hope it works, or write a DuckDB SQL query against an S3 bucket.
For a lot of us, that's half a day gone before we even open QGIS.
Section 3. Solution 020-040
I built something that skips all of that. Go to hienko.com, Tools Overture Downloader.
You get a map? Just draw a rectangle around your area of interest.
Pick your data set. Buildings, places, roads, addresses.
Hit download. That's it.
GeoJSON lands straight in your downloads folder, ready to drag into QGIS or ArcGIS.
Section 4. Proof. Arrow 41. Watch.
I'm grabbing building footprints for the Melbourne CBD right now.
Bounding box drawn. Building selected. Downloading. Done.
No installs, no credits burned, no terminal.
Section 5. CTA-10-WALK-115
It's completely free to use.
Link's in the description.
If this saved you time, subscribe.
I'm building more tools like this.