Hook. My ArcGIS credits ran out downloading building data. There's a better way.
Platform. YouTube. Shorts. 9x16. Duration. 50s.
Audience. Urban Planner.
Section 1. Hook. 0-0-0-0-5.
I burned through half my ArcGIS credits just trying to pull building footprints for a single suburb.
Section 2. The better way.
0 0 5 0 25
Overture Maps has all of that data for free, globally.
The problem was actually getting it without a Python environment or SQL skills.
So I built a browser tool that does it differently.
You go to hienko.com tools Overture Downloader,
draw your area on the map, select buildings, and click Download.
GeoJSON. Done. Costs nothing.
Section 3. Who it's for. 0 25 0 40.
If you're in planning, local government, or just sick of watching your credits drain, this is made for you.
Section 4. CTA 040-050. Link in bio. Free tool. No sign-up.