Hook DuckDB vs. Overture Downloader. Same data, very different experience.
Platform YouTube 16-X9. Duration 90s.
Audience GS Analyst. Section 1. Setup 0.0.0.0.8.
There are a few ways to get Overture Maps data.
I'm going to show you two of them side by side so you can decide which fits your workflow.
Section 2. The Hard Way 08040
Method 1. The official Python CLI.
Install overture maps via pip, look up your bounding box coordinates from a separate tool,
format them as west-south-east-north, run the download command, specify your output format, wait.
It works, but if your pip environment is broken or you haven't touched the terminal in a while,
that quick data pull turns into a debugging session.
Method 2. DuckDB. Write a SQL query against S3. Make sure your region is set correctly.
Understand Geoparquet enough to export it properly.
Again, totally valid if that's your world, but it's a lot of setup for,
I just need the roads for this district.
Section 3. The Fast Way. 040-110
Method 3. The Overture Downloader at hanko.com slash tools slash Overture Downloader.
Open browser. Draw a rectangle on the map over your area. Pick your data set. Download.
GeoJSON is in your folder in under a minute. Same Overture data. Zero setup.
Section 4. Verdict 110-130.
If you work with Overture regularly and live in the terminal, the CLI is great.
If you need data quickly, you're on a shared computer, or you're handing this off to a non-developer,
the browser tool is just faster. Both are free. Link to both in the description.