Hook, get global building data for your thesis study area, free in 60 seconds.
Platform, TikTok 9x16, duration 45s, audience, researcher student, section 1, Hook 0-Seok-005.
If you need spatial data for your research and you don't have an ArcGIS license, listen up.
Section 2, what it is, 0-0-5-0-15.
Overture Maps is a free, open data set backed by Amazon, Microsoft, and Meta.
Global buildings, roads, POIs, addresses, all free, but downloading it normally requires Python or Suckle.
Section 3. The Tool. 01Feev 035.
I built a browser tool, the Overture Downloader.
You go to heenko.com tools slash Overture Downloader, draw a box around your study area on the map,
pick your data set, let's say places, and hit download. You get a GeoJSON file you can open in
QGIS R or Python instantly. Section 4. CTA 035 045. No account, no cost, no install.
Link in bio. And yes, it works for international areas too.